Alexander Yatskov

Serbia



kuein@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/alexander-yatskov-009622173

Summary

Software developer with 15+ years of experience, went from junior to CTO but return to most comfort position of middle-senior backend developer. Last 7+ years working as independent contractor in web-programming and data processing spheres. Last two years slowly but steady migrate from Python to Go(lang) and Rust and from classic monolithic architecture to serverless & microservices architecture.

Programming skills: Python, PostgreSQL, AWS, MongoDB, Golang, Rust Domain knowledge (industries with past experience): blockchain, fintech and data processing

Experience



Software Developer

May 2017 - Present (5 years 10 months)

This is legal entity for freelance contracts on Upwork. More than 6 years of working there bring me Top Rated Plus status and 100% job success (Profile: https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/ayatskov).

Mostly python jobs, a lot of data processing and data scraping. Some blockchain experience, serverless experience with AWS, software architecture and API integration



Lead Python developer

Qualimental Technologies

Dec 2021 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Web application builded on Pyramid framework, allows access to several NLP models related to British law corpus (https://lawnotion.co.uk/). I am responsible for most of backend development of this project last years + refactoring a lot of legacy code.

Tech stack: Python. Pyramid, MongoDB, Postgresql.



Back End Developer

Growth Channel

Oct 2019 - Aug 2021 (1 year 11 months)

Startup in digital marketing (https://growthchannel.io/)

I was one of first persons hired by them, created first and second version of backend infrastructure as AWS SAM, so project mostly involved third-party API integration, Python/Go Lambdas, payment processing (Stripe), MongoDB & DynamoDB



Data Specialist

EVA.AI | Powering HR 4.0

Nov 2018 - Mar 2019 (5 months)

I was hired here as Python developer for refactoring old codebase, but in process focus of my involvement slightly changed to Machine Learning problems. In the end, we created and tested several ML systems, which included NLP analytics for CV and Job descriptions for English, Russian and French language, recommendation engine, based on hybrid principles and several prediction models based on scikit-learn.

Python Developer

PPTbuilder

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018 (3 months)

Data visualization startup, based on flask + HighCharts.js

My task was polished codebase before release, user management system, creating admin dashboard for owners. Conservative technostack: Python 3, flask, PostgreSQL

Python Developer

DB2 Management OÜ

Sep 2017 - Jul 2018 (11 months)

E-shops and system direct management of them, like a Shopify, but home-brew.

Stack: Flask + MongoDB, third-part APIs, payments gateways, e-shops. Integration with payment system like Payu and Stripe, Facebook Advertise API, Google Adwords and other advertise systems. Integration with legacy codebase, code refactoring, documenting and optimization. Single-handedly develop and create system for mass adverts publication in several marketing platforms on several languages.

Python Developer

Bart Jellema

Jun 2017 - Sep 2017 (4 months)

Web scraping data from cryptocurrency trade platforms. Task was gather as much as possible information from cryptocurrency exchange platforms around the world. A lot of documentation reading, third-part API integrations, occasionally penetration testing, pure Python without any framework. Total amount of scraped platform ~50

Python Developer

REIS EU

May 2017 - Aug 2017 (4 months)

Django REST-framework backend engineer. This project was about Spanish realty, half-done on moment of my entering into project. Backend was on DRF with session auth, so. my tasks was fixed several endpoints, creating new one for CRUD and code refactoring and optimization.

S/ Backend developer

semilimes Inc.

Nov 2016 - Jan 2017 (3 months)

Web-based CRM system for small and mid-size business. I was a developer who develop user authentication and social networks logins for this project. Technological stack: Python 2.7, flask and Docker.

Education



Altai State University

None, Social Psychology 2000 - 2003

Licenses & Certifications



Getting Started with Go - Cours

C7F7MXGQBJBA





Introduction to Genomic - The Johns Hopkins University

Skills

Mongo • Stripe (Software) • Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) • AWS Lambda • Natural Language Processing (NLP) • Data Pipelines • AWS SAM • Go (Programming Language) • Rust (Programming Language) • Solidity